Guide to the Time Inc. Realia Collection 1937-2015 MS 3009-RG 48
New-York Historical Society
Time Inc. Realia Collection
1937-2015
New-York Historical Society
Time, inc.
MS 3009-RG 48
28 Linear feet in 24 containers of various sizes
The collection is composed of a wide variety of objects collected by the Time Inc. Archives. The most common type of objects are those given to advertisers as a promotional gimmick to encourage advertisment in Time Inc. magazines, awards given to Time Inc., its magazines, or staff, and items branded with the logos of Time Inc. magazines given to Time Inc. employees as gifts or to subscribers as promotions.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials in this collection are stored offsite. For more information on making arrangements to consult them, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Unreformatted digital material in the collection is not accessible.
Arrangement
Arrangement is alphabetical and was devised. The material's physical storage does not reflect this arrangement; items are housed for safety and preservation.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Time Inc. in 2015.
Related Materials
This finding aid relates to just one record group of the Time Inc. Records. For information about the other record groups and for overall information about the archives, please see the Guide to the Time Inc. Records (MS 3009). The Henry Luce Papers (MS 3014) were acquired with the Time Inc. Records. The collection of books acquired with the records are cataloged as the Time Inc. Reference Library.
Scope and Contents
The collection is composed of a wide variety of objects collected by the Time Inc. Archives. The most common type of objects are those given to advertisers as a promotional gimmick to encourage advertisment in Time Inc. magazines, awards given to Time Inc., its magazines, or staff, and items branded with the logos of Time Inc. magazines given to Time Inc. employees as gifts or to subscribers as promotions.
Advertising.; Corporation records.; Corporations -- History.; Corporations -- New York (State) -- New York.; Organization files.; Promotional materials.; Publishers and publishing -- New York (State) -- New York.; Time, inc. -- Archives.; Time, inc. -- History.
- Elections: Assorted Political Campaign Buttons, circa 1975-1995 (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 1-3)
- Elections: Set of Reproduction Presidential Campaign Buttons 1896-1974, 1976 (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 4)
- Fortune 500: The Business Game, circa 1980 (Offsite-box 4245, Item 1)
- Fortune: 1973 Desk Diary, 1972 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 1)
- Fortune: 1984 Desk Diary, 1983 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 2)
- Fortune: 1991 Desk Diary, 1990 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 3)
- Fortune: 1992 Desk Diary, 1991 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 4)
- Fortune: Paperweight Marked "Biweekly Fortune First Anniversary", circa 1979 (Offsite-box 4177, Item 3)
- Fortune: Tile, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 1)
- Fortune: Yi Augury Set with President Label, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 8)
- Health: min's Editorial and Design Awards Magazine Design/Single Issue (Consumer) Award, 2013 (Offsite-box 4175, Item 3)
- Henry Luce: 21 Jewel Square Club Distinguished Service Award, 1962 (Offsite-box 4164, Item 1)
- Henry Luce: Frank M. Hawke Memorial Award by Air Service Post 501 of the American Legion, 1956 (Offsite-box 4164, Item 4)
- Henry Luce: Hadden/Luce Medal Case (empty), 1973 (Offsite-box 4178, Item 5)
- Henry Luce: Souvenir Statue Marking 25th Anniversary of Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, 1956 (Offsite-box 4163, Item 7)
- Life: 1982 Desktop Diary, 1981 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 1)
- Life: 1983 Desktop Diary, 1982 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 2)
- Life: 1984 Desktop Diary, 1983 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 3)
- Life: 1985 Desktop Diary, 1984 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 4)
- Life: 1986 Desktop Diary, 1985 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 5)
- Life: 1987 Desktop Diary, 1986 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 6)
- Life: 1991 Calendar, 1990 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 7)
- Life: "Advertised in Life" Stickers, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 6)
- Life: "Advertised in Life" Sticker, undated (Offsite-box 4253, Item 2)
- Life: Alfred Eisenstaedt: Calendar, 1995 (Offsite-box 4165, Item 1)
- Life: Alfred Eisenstaedt: Commemorative Plaque, 1995 (Offsite-box 4173, Item 1)
- Life: Alfred Eisenstaedt: Greeting Cards, circa 1995 (Offsite-box 4165, Item 2)
- Life: Alfred Eisenstaedt: Plaque for Photography and Photojournalism Presented by Mayor of Woodbridge Township James E. McGreevey, 1984 (Offsite-box 4165, Item 3)
- Life: Case for Life Issues to Mark Birth-Month of Child (empty), undated (Offsite-box 4174, Item 1)
- Life: Ceramic Mug, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 7)
- Life: Board Game, 1985 (Offsite-box 4169, Item 1)
- Life: Board Game, 1985 (Offsite-box 4169, Item 2)
- Life: Bowl and Spoon Set, circa 1983 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 11)
- Life: Case for Newsstand Bracelet (empty), undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 23)
- Life: Cube-Maze Puzzle, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 4)
- Life: Direct Mail Leaders Award, 1956 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 3)
- Life: Andrew Heiskell: Distinguished Achievement Award from Newsdealers Post 1169 of the American Legion, 1955 (Offsite-box 4164, Item 2)
- Life: The Face of Life Windows Software in Large Box, 1994 (Offsite-box 4167, Item 5)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes digital material: 1 computer disc (CD-ROM)
- Life: The Face of Life Windows Software in Cardboard CD Package, 1994 (Offsite-box 4167, Item 6)
- Life: "Featuring Products Advertised in Life" banner, undated (Offsite-box 4253, Item 1)
- Life: Freedoms Foundation Inc. 2nd place General Award Medallion, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 6)
- Life: Giant Clothes Pin, undated (Offsite-box 4159, Item 5-6)
- Life: G.I. Joe D-Day Figure with Miniature Life Magazine, 2001 (Offsite-box 4159, Item 8)
- Life: Henry R. Luce Award Finalist Plaque to Isolde Motley, undated (Offsite-box 4165, Item 4)
- Life: Imitation Film Reel in Tin, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 8)
- Life: Imitation Menswear Tags in Box, undated (Offsite-box 4159, Item 8)
- Life: I.U.L. Achievement Award, 1953 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 13)
- Life: La Belle Award for Color Photography, Presented in Cooperation with the Photographic Society of America, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 14)
- Life: Life/N.W. Ayer Letter-Opener, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 22)
- Life: Luggage Tag, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 17)
- Life: Manhattan "Advertised in Life" Bean-Bag Paperweight, undated (Offsite-box 4159, Item 3)
- Life: Margaret Bourke-White: Plaque from The Society of Professional Journalists Sigma Delta Chi, 1984 (Offsite-box 4173, Item 2)
- Life: Metal Display Frame for Newsstands, undated (Offsite-box 4162, Item 6)
- Life: Noise-Maker, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 15)
- Life: Oven Mitt, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 13)
- Life: Oversized Paperclip, circa 1987 (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 8)
- Life: Photographic Society of America Progress Award, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 17)
- Life: Poor Richard Club Award for Merit, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 26)
- Life: Rain Poncho, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 2)
- Life: Robert Capa: Medallion by "Robert Capa's Friends at Life and the Overseas Press Club of America", undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 15)
- Life: Robert Capa: Robert Capa Award Medallion, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 16)
- Life: Salt-Shaker-Shaped Jar, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 10)
- Life: Sign for Beach-Related Promotional Item, undated (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 5)
- Life: Sign for Jell-O Spoon Promotion (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 6)
- Life: Sign for Umbrella Promotion, undated (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 7)
- Life: Stickers, undated (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 9)
- Life: Stadium Seat, undated (Offsite-box 4174, Item 2)
- Life: Suspenders, undated (Offsite-box 4253, Item 3)
- People: Warden-Brooks tie "made exclusively for People", undated (Offsite-box 4253, Item 4)
- Life: Toy Top, 1986 (Offsite-box 4168, Item 3)
- Life: University of Missouri Medallion, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 20)
- Life: Valentine's Day Heart-Shaped Pillow, 1983 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 5)
- The March of Time: Exhibitor Laurel Awards 1950-51, 1951 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 4)
- The March of Time: Grand Shorts Award, 1937 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 10)
- The March of Time: Grand Shorts Award, 1938 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 11)
- The March of Time: Grand Shorts Award to "The Refugees, Today and Tomorrow", 1939 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 12)
- Money: Christmas Stocking, undated (Offsite-box 4175, Item 1)
- Money: Metal Rendition of the Letter "M", undated (Offsite-box 4171, Item 1)
- Money: Metal Rendition of the Letter "O", undated (Offsite-box 4171, Item 2)
- Money: Metal Rendition of the Letter "N", undated (Offsite-box 4172, Item 1)
- Money: Metal Rendition of the Letter "E", undated (Offsite-box 4172, Item 2)
- Money: Metal Rendition of the Letter "Y", undated (Offsite-box 4172, Item 3)
- Money: Necktie with Money Bag Pattern, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 9)
- Money: Towel with Logo, undated (Offsite-box 4175, Item 2)
- People: 25th Anniversary Weekly Calendar, 1998 (Offsite-box 4167, Item 4)
- People: 1979 Desktop Diary, 1978 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 8)
- People: 1983 Desktop Diary, 1982 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 8)
- People: Frisbee, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 3)
- People: Inflatable Raft, 1981 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 8)
- People: Luggage Tag, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 18)
- People: Satin Clothes Hangers, 1981 (Offsite-box 4169, Item 5)
- People: Tennis Racket Cover, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 2)
- People Weekly the Trivia Game, circa 1984 (Offsite-box 4245, Item 2)
- Picture Week: Magazine Rack, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 11)
- Sports Illustrated: "Game-Time Recipes" Pamphlet, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 22)
- Sports Illustrated: Kids Basketball Jersey, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 22)
- Sports Illustrated: Kids T-shirt, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 23-24)
- Sports Illustrated: Notebook with Leather Cover, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 19)
- Sports Illustrated: Olympic Pins in Case, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 10)
- Sports Illustrated: Seat Cushion, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 6)
- Time: 50th Anniversary Medallion, 1986 (Offsite-box 4253, Item 5)
- Time: 75th Anniversary Mug, 2011 (Offsite-box 4159, Item 7)
- Time: 100 Men and Women of the Century LCD Display, circa 1998 (Offsite-box 4178, Item 3)
- Time: 1985 Calendar, 1984 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 10)
- Time: 1994 Almanac Software (Offsite-box 4169, Item 4)
- Time: Accordion-fold decoration with writing "In Union is Strength", circa 1976 (Offsite-box 4177, Item 7)
- Time: Accordion-fold decoration with writing "Union Forever", circa 1976 (Offsite-box 4177, Item 6)
- Time: Ashtray, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 24)
- Time: "Award" from John F. Murphy Criticizing Time for Harming "Ike", circa 1955 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 2)
- Time: Board Game, 1979 (Offsite-box 4169, Item 3)
- Time: Bandana, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 1)
- Time: Box of Cards promoting "A Big Year to be in Time", 1960 (Offsite-box 4159, Item 2)
- Time: Canvas Bag, undated (Offsite-box 4163, Item 2)
- Time: Circulation Fact Cards for Various Cities, 1979 (Offsite-box 4178, Item 9)
- Time: Cocktail Napkin Set, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 4-5)
- Time: Folding One-Yard Ruler Promoting Time's Redesign, 1992 (Offsite-box 4159, Item 1)
- Time: George Polk Memorial Award to Time Essay from Long Island University, 1966 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 7)
- Time: George Polk Memorial Award to Time Essay from Long Island University, 1967 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 8)
- Time: Golf Club Covers, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 8)
- Time: Henry R. Luce Awards Best Achievement in Cross-Platform Innovation to Time and Time.com, 2012 (Offsite-box 4175, Item 5)
- Time: Henry R. Luce Awards News Photography to Time, 2015 (Offsite-box 4175, Item 6)
- Time: Leather Passport Cases, 1990 (Offsite-box 4166, Item 14-20)
- Time: Luggage Tag, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 19)
- Time: Magazine Covers Mug, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 10)
- Time: Memo-Holder, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 10-11)
- Time: Memo-Holder, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 3)
- Time: Millennium Countdown Clock, circa 1999 (Offsite-box 4162, Item 16)
- Time: Neckties, 1972 (Offsite-box 4170, Item 1-6)
- Time: Notepaper Tray, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 2)
- Time: Paperclip Desk Ornament, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 5)
- Time: Paper-Tape Dispenser with Marking "Your Products Travel First Class in Time", undated (Offsite-box 4159, Item 11)
- Time: Paperweight, silver color, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 2)
- Time: Paperweight with Map Decoration, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 8)
- Time: Paperweight, Approximately Eight Inches Long, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 15-16)
- Time: Paperweight, Approximately Five Inches Long, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 14)
- Time: Paperweight, Approximately Seven Inches Long, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 13)
- Time: Paperweight, Approximately Two Inches Long, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 12)
- Time: Paperweight with Marking "Sell it in Time", undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 18)
- Time: Pen, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 13)
- Time: Pencil, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 14)
- Time: Plastic Coasters, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 20)
- Time: Plastic Mug, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 8)
- Time: Promotional Soviet Union Necktie, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 6)
- Time: Set of Revolutionary War Pewter Coat Button Reproductions (Promotional Item), 1976 (Offsite-box 4178, Item 23-25)
- Time: Ribbon, undated (Offsite-box 4165, Item 5)
- Time: Rubber Mallet with Label "Strike a Nerve" in Box, undated (Offsite-box 4160, Item 11)
- Time: Rubber Mallet with Label "Strike a Nerve", undated (Offsite-box 4162, Item 12)
- Time: Scarf with Time Cartoons, 1994 (Offsite-box 4159, Item 2)
- Time: Shower Curtain, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 11)
- Time: "Strategic Advertising" Pamphlets Boxed Set, undated (Offsite-box 4162, Item 13)
- Time: Tile with "Advertised in Time" Image Promoting Tourism to France, 1956 (Offsite-box 4160, Item 10)
- Time: Tile, undated (Offsite-box 4159, Item 20)
- Time: "Time 50" Banner, 1986 (Offsite-box 4168, Item 1)
- Time: Time/Canadian Club Whiskey Long-Neck Matches, undated (Offsite-box 4168, Item 6)
- Time: Time: The Game, undated (Offsite-box 4165, Item 6)
- Time: "Time Recycles" Button, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 11-12)
- Time: Time Wall Clock, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 12)
- Time Inc.: Bundle of Tiny Pencils Imprinted with Names of Time Inc. Magazines, undated (Offsite-box 4178, Item 7)
- Time Inc.: Certificate of Appreciation from National Association of Minority Women in Business, undated (Offsite-box 4164, Item 5)
- Time Inc.: Eisie: Alfred Eisenstaedt Award for Magazine Photography Souvenir Photo Album, 1998 (Offsite-box 4283, Item 2)
- Time Inc.: Financial World Annual Report Award for Best 1962 Annual Report, 1963 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 5)
- Time Inc.: Framed Fragment of Editor-in-Chief's "Pope's Miter", undated (Offsite-box 4253, Item 7)
- Time Inc.: Framed Specimen of $10,000 Security Note, 1976 (Offsite-box 4164, Item 3)
- Time Inc.: Good Turn Award from Boy Scouts for Sponsoring Communication Arts Lunch-o-ree, 1974 (Offsite-box 4161, Item 9)
- Time Inc.: ID Card Holder, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 16)
- Time Inc.: National Sales Executives, Inc. Plaque for Annual Contribution as Youth Education Sponsor, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 18)
- Time Inc.: Paperweight Marked "Time & Life Building 1968", circa 1968 (Offsite-box 4178, Item 17)
- Time Inc.: Pen-Stand, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 25)
- Time Inc.: Sailor's Hat, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 7)
- Time Inc.: Trophy Labeled "Edso Sports Time Inc. Division I Champions", 1999 (Offsite-box 4163, Item 5)
- Time Inc.: Wall Labels for Museum Exhibit, undated (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 10)
- Time International: 40th Anniversary Timezone Reader, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 9)
  General
  May be a part of a larger object that is not part of this collection.
- Time/Life: Keychain, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 8)
- Time-Life Photo Center: Baseball Cap, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 9)
- Time-Life: Series 550 Piece Puzzle: Casts of Africa: African Lynx, 1990 (Offsite-box 4283, Item 7)
- Time-Life: Series 550 Piece Puzzle: Casts of Africa: Cheetah, 1990 (Offsite-box 4283, Item 8)
- Time Life Video: Speed Reading with Dick Cavett, 1986 (Offsite-box 4282, Item 1)
- Time-Life Photo Center: Party Balloons, undated (Offsite-box 4177, Item 20-21)
- Time-Life Photo Laboratories: Mousepad, undated (Offsite-box 4176, Folder 11)
- Timepix: Bag, undated (Offsite-box 4161, Item 21)
- Unknown: 1964-65 World's Fair Medallion with 300th Anniversary of Founding of New York City on Reverse (Offsite-box 4161, Item 1)
- Unknown: 16mm Film Splicer, undated (Offsite-box 4163, Item 1)
- Unknown: American Flag-Themed Paper Plates, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 1)
- Unknown: Audio Cassettes in Christmas Stocking Packaging with Card for "Our Friends in the Worlds of Consumer Electronics and Entertainment", 1988 (Offsite-box 4166, Item 1-13)
- Unknown: Blue Conductor's Cap with Canvas Cloth Tucked Inside, undated (Offsite-box 4167, Item 1)
- Unknown: Bust of Johannes Gutenberg with Separate Wooden Base, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 4)
- Unknown: Bust of Johannes Gutenberg with Separate Wooden Base, undated (Offsite-box 4283, Item 5)
- Unknown: Metal Sculpture of Old Glory Flag, undated (Offsite-box 4162, Item 7)
- Unknown: National Magazine Awards "Ellie" Award, 2013 (Offsite-box 4175, Item 4)
- Unknown: Printing Rod, undated (Offsite-box 4162, Item 9)
- Unknown: Trophy Base Labeled "Eddie Velez", undated (Offsite-box 4163, Item 4)
- Unknown: Trophy Base Labeled "Sgt. Gloria Gay Best Manager-Treasurer Mar. 17 1950 – Oct. 12 2000" (Offsite-box 4163, Item 6)
- Washington Star: Necktie, undated (Offsite-box 4170, Item 8)